Jesus' name must be honoured.
(Amen!)
Thank you.
Thank You, Lord.
You listen to the message, "Jesus' name must be honoured".
For Jesus' name to be honoured.
That is the question, "How can Jesus' name be honoured?"
John asked me to call you - you refuse to answer - that is not honour.
You say, "John, John!" - and John refuses to hear you, or you refuse to hear John - that is not honour.
You say, "John, John!" - no response - that is not honour.
For Jesus' name to be honoured - is a "million dollars" question.
"Kinsly, Kinsly!" - no response.
For Jesus' name to be honoured.
That is a question for everyone of us.
The question is, 'Is Jesus' name being honoured?'
Viewers, we know you are there and we can feel it.
You are with us and we are with you.
Distance is not a barrier and your Bible is there with you.
Let's quickly look at the Book of John 6, verse 63.
Viewers, going by the song we've just sung now, "Jesus' name must be honoured.
Jesus' name must be honoured in my life everyday."
Is this being honoured in your life?
That is the question.
John 6:63 says, "The Spirit gives life; the flesh counts for nothing.
The Words I have spoken to you – they are full of the Spirit and life."
And you know that Christ and the Word are one.
Here in John 6:63 it says, "The Spirit gives life; the flesh counts for nothing.
The Words I have spoken to you – they are full of the Spirit and life."
Go also down, to the verse 65, "He went on to say, 'This is why I told you that no one can come to Me
unless the Father has enabled them.'"
You can't just wake up and say, "I'm going to Jesus" - you must be enabled.
This means you must be enabled and energised.
You can't just say, "I'm a child of God."
A lot of people say, "I'm a child of God" today.
There are many children of God, who say, "Jesus is Lord".
You don't need licence to do that.
Now, going by that John 6:65, "No one can come to Me unless he is enabled."
This means, for Jesus' name to be honoured, God's Word must be Spirit and life.
We have the language of today and the language of the Bible that saves, creates and rules over us.
For Jesus' name to be honoured, God's Word must be Spirit and life.
It's not just to be born of the Word but you must be born of the Spirit.
Because the Word refreshes our mind and the Spirit renews our strength.
This means, two things must join, merge and come together – the Spirit and the Word.
Two things must join and merge – the Spirit and the Word – to be born again,
for the name of Jesus to be honoured.
It's not just to say, "Be healed!"
It must be Spirit and life.
The power of God must go through the Word and the Spirit to bring about that.
That is, when you see God, you see power.
God must drive through the Spirit and the Word to bring about that.
The Word dominating you is the Lordship of Christ in you.
By meditation, the Word can dominate.
It dominates us through meditation, obeying, acting and reading.
Meditation is a visit to Him.
This is to say that the Word has priority over His name.
The Word has priority over His name.
This is why when you call the name "Jesus, in Jesus' name"...
Even in your dreams people come to attack you and you say, "Jesus!" but they keep attacking and beating you.
Or, after the attack you say "Jesus!".
You want to say "Jesus!" before the attack but there is no enablement, energy, power or grace.
Jesus' name is not to be called after the attack.
Anyone can say, "Thank You, Jesus" after the miracle but not everyone can say, "Jesus" before the miracle.
When you see the miracle is about to happen, you will be looking at it, "Will this happen? How will this happen?"
You will want to see how it will happen, "Can this happen?" - you will be looking at it.
When the miracle happens, "Jesus!" - but before it happens...
It takes faith to say, "Jesus"...
It takes faith to say, "Jesus, thank You" before the miracle
but anyone can say, "Jesus, thank You" after the miracle.
As you are sitting down, you have pain and challenges.
It takes faith to say, "Thank You, Jesus, It's over".
But it doesn’t take anything to say, "Jesus, thank You" when it is over.
After being healed, "Thank You, Jesus" - but now to say "Thank You, Jesus" - it takes faith.
Faith is expecting Jesus to do what He has promised to do – that is faith.
The man of faith will say, "Thank You, Jesus for blessing me" before blessing
but today, we say, "Thank You, Jesus" after blessing.
God's Word has power over His name - yes.
By the Word, we are saved.
It is the Word of God that has taught us the value, authority of the name Jesus
and our legal right to use the name, Jesus.
Anybody can use the name, Jesus but how many have the right to use the name?
How many of you can say, "Jesus" and Jesus will come to the scene?
So, until you have the legal right of using the name...
He said, "In My name you shall cast out demons" and you say, "In Jesus' name, out demon!" -
without the Word of God dominating your heart.
It is when the Word dominates your heart, it influences your character and thoughts
it influences your character and conduct.
"In My name you shall cast out demons" - yes, Bible says this.
I walk towards a demon and say, "In Jesus' name - be delivered!"
God's Word has priority over His name.
How would that happen?
How will you bring Jesus to the scene?
It is impossible.
If you don’t have God's Word, you have nothing at all.
If you don’t have God's Word, you cannot bring Jesus onto the scene.
You say, "Jesus!" and Jesus says, "What are you saying? What do you want?"
So, your song:
Jesus must be honoured
In my life every day
How can Jesus be honoured when the Word is not dominating your heart?
It is when God's Word dominates your heart, it can influence your character, thoughts and conduct.
Your character before now: "I don't know if it will happen. Can this be happening?"
When God's Word dominates your heart, it changes your perception, the way you reason.
"This will happen. It can happen. This is God's Word."
It is God's Word that builds faith in the believers.
Christ can only come to your heart through faith; your heart is His dwelling place.
That is where He dwells; the panel where He controls you, the contact point – your heart.
That is why the Bible says faith is of man's heart.
By living in the Word and by the Word living in us, we have the legal right to use the name of Jesus.
We have the legal right to the name Jesus.
Yes - Jesus!
Look at the Book of Mark 16 verse 18:
"They shall lay hands on the sick and they shall recover."
This means nothing will ever happen without acting on the Word.
Nothing, unless we act on the Word.
Because the Word has priority over His name.
This is why you keep praying for people, "Be healed"...
Bible says, "They shall lay hands on the sick and they shall recover".
Because...
the Word gives value, authority and legal right.
When you call, "Jesus" without the Word, it is like you are calling your brother at home.
Many of your brothers have name Jesus.
Many people out there bear the name Jesus.
They say their own name is Jesus.
It is like calling somebody among you without the Word.
This is what you are facing.
No one can say, "Jesus is the Healer", no one can say, "Jesus is Lord",
no one can say, "Jesus is the Redeemer", unless he is guided by the Holy Spirit.
You must be guided.
We want to be like Jesus.
The Holy Spirit is our guide.
Tell your neighbour, "I want to be like Jesus. The Holy Spirit is my guide."
He must be the One to guide you to be like Him.
He must guide you to be like Jesus.
It is not like imitating your father at home, observing what your father is doing.
My father has a beard - me too, I need to have a beard.
This is the way my father walks - I need to walk like that.
That is an imitation of a man.
Imitation of God – I want to be like Jesus; the Holy Spirit is my guide.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Inner my heart
You listen to that?
Inner my heart.
I want you to open your mouth and say, "Thank You, Jesus for giving me faith to believe."
You hear what verse 65 of John 6 is saying.
It says, "No one can come to Me unless he is guided, enabled."
Say, "Thank You, Jesus for giving me faith to believe."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is it.
I want to be like Jesus - Holy Spirit is my guide.
I cannot just wake up and say, "I want to be like Jesus. This is the way Jesus walks. I will read my Bible.
Let me see what the Bible says about Jesus - I will follow what the Bible says about Jesus" - no.
Following Jesus...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to be like Jesus - Holy Spirit is my guide.
He guides me, "Thank You, Jesus for giving me faith to believe" - this his how I offer my prayer.
"Thank You, Jesus for giving me faith to believe."
Only faith pleases Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You need to say that.
I know this is the first time you think about that this way, "You need faith to believe?"
He has said it.
It is the Word that has taught us the authority to say, "Leave, come, go!"
The Word of God taught us.
That Word must be Spirit and life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He has promised He will never fail
I will follow Him
His faithfulness
Listen to that.
His faithfulness.
That is why no matter what you are going through if life, declare God's faithfulness.
No matter what you are going through, no matter the situation you are in, declare God's faithfulness.
Whether He heals you or not, He is God.
He is Lord
Amen
Whether you are blessed or not...
He is Lord
Amen
That is it.
Tell your neighbour,
"No matter what you are going through, no matter your situation, declare God's faithfulness."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Stand up to declare God's faithfulness, no matter the challenges
because He has made a way where there is no way for you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is how to overcome all those things you are facing.
You see what happened to Daniel in the lion's den and to Meshach, Shadrach, Abed-Nego in the furnace.
What manner of man is Jesus
Hallelujah
That is over to you.
What manner of man is Jesus in my life I know.
In your life you know it is different.
No matter what you are going through - tell your neighbour, "Declare God's faithfulness".
(No matter what you are going through, declare God's faithfulness.)
I cannot hear you.
Because I am sensing God's deliverance.
(Amen.)
I am sensing God's way out for you.
No matter what you are going through, all you need is to declare God's faithfulness.
Rise up.
Will you open your lips and begin to declare God's faithfulness in your life.
No matter what you are going through...
In Jesus' name!
(Amen.)
That's all.
Just declare God's faithfulness and see what comes next!
If your declaration comes from the heart - oh my God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask your neighbour, "Is your declaration coming from the heart?"
(Is your declaration coming from the heart?)
I cannot hear you.
You mean it?
(You mean it?)
Your declaration comes from the heart?
(Your declaration comes from the heart?)
If your declaration comes from the heart...
The SCOAN Sunday Service